CV David Skødt Lauritsen

Tønballevej 5 7130 Juelsminde

Age: 27

Phone: 51 51 18 97 Mail: seqlog@gmail.com

LinkedIn profil: linkedIn.com/in/DavidSkodt Website (work in progress): davidskodt.com

Personal & professional profile

I'm David, nice to meet you! I recently acquired a passion for User Experience (UX) design. In March, 2017, I decided to work towards becoming a full-blown UX designer through self-study. My education (M. Sc. In Medialogy with a Specialization in Interaction) had introduced me to the role of the UXer already, but at the time, it didn't interest me. It took some time away from my studies to realize that UX is my calling. I set out to make myself familiar with terminology and practices, and I started strategizing when I was in the middle of my stay at Aalborg Sportshøjskole. Through books, articles, video courses and through doing, I improved my skills and began to engage in small projects to hone my skills in User Experience Design. I am still at it, too, improving by the day!

Aside from my personal projects, I enjoy working in teams the most. I consider myself a team player who enjoys both the social dynamics of working as a team, but also the positive influence it can have on bettering yourself in your field. The most recent examples of me working in teams have been through my volunteer work with Red Barnet Ungdom, during my stay at Aalborg Sportshøjskole and through my research during my university years. My time at Aalborg University lead to three publications of which I am very proud.

Education

Oct 2016 - Jun 2017

Student at Aalborg Sportshøjskole

• There was a lot of weight put on team building and solving practical problems. During my stay, I also used my spare time to improve my UX related skills and create my online portfolio website.

Aug 2013 – Jun 2015

Master of Science in Medialogy with a Specialization in Interaction

 Thesis title: Aurally Aided Visual Search Performance Comparing Virtual Audio Systems (published through Audio Engineering Society, presented at the "137th AES Conference" in Los Angeles, USA)

Aug 2010 – Jun 2013

Bachelor of Science in Medialogy, Aalborg University

- Study focus: Interaction design, UX, programming, esthetics, objective- and subjective trials, sound, human perception and statistics.
- Individual focus: 3D sound w/ HRTF, presence (immersion), image processing, system design, C++/C#, user experience.
- Thesis: Differences in human audio localization performance between a HRTF- and a non-HRTF audio system (published through the Association for Computing Machinery, presented at the "8th Audio Mostly Conference" in Pitå, Sweden).

Work Experience

Apr 2016 – Oct 2016

Temp teacher at Glud Skole, teaching maths, Danish, English, history and religion

Tasked full-time with a class of 5th graders, I took it upon myself to structure their curriculum, write home and host the parent-teacher meeting

Aug 2014 - Dec 2014

Internship at VOLUME (read more on portfolio site)

- Internship that replaced the 9. semester in my M. Sc. at Aalborg University
- I got to work on Local Heroes, one of the projects they hoped to bring to the U.S.
- Focus on interaction, user-friendliness, gamification and scaling on a web-based platform
- Assisting coworkers and boss with general computer issues

Pre-2012

Temp work for "Vikarene" in Horsens, 4 months of elective military boot camp at Varde Kaserne, temp teacher at Glud Skole

Volunteer Work

Oct 2016 - Jun 2017

Voulenteer at Red Barnet Ungdom (Independent Save the Children youth project)

- Voulenteer work where we go to an asylum center bimonthly to engage the children there with play, activities and cultural events.
- I have been a very active volunteer, attended meetings and visits alike as well as directed and edited a music video intended for fun and promotion (the video can be viewed on portfolio website).

Aug 2013 – Jun 2015

Matcher at AAU Matchmaking

- Volunteer work with focus on establishing contact and cooperation between students at Aalborg University and local companies.
- Focus on communication and networking.

Software Qualifications

Programming languages: HTML, CSS (and Bootstrap), Javascript, C#/C++, ActionScript 3.0.

Software experience: Illustrator, Unity3D, Game Maker, Maya, 3DS Max, Sony Vegas, Photoshop, LaTeX.

Microsoft office: Experienced with all office products.

Lingual Skills

Danish: Fluent (5/5), English: Fluent (5/5), German: Good (3/5), Spanish: Fair (2/5)

Hobbies and Interests

In the summer of 2015, I headed out on an epic journey: the Appalachian Trail. For about ~2.900 kilometers over a period of 6 months, I hiked a trail that crosses 14 state lines on the east coast of the US. While arduous, the trip was a great experience and it provided plenty of learning experiences. It has made me a very confident individual who dares to try, in all things. In life, I am a very optimistic individual who loves the outdoors, good food and rock climbing.